Finding Aid for the Los Angeles Unified School District Board of Education Records LSC.1923
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Subject Files, 1913-2012
  - Affirmative Action, 1969 June 12-1996 July 15 (Box 864, Folder 1-3)
    Board motions/resolutions, Committee Reports and correspondence on proposed changes to federal ethnic/racial definitions and categories and unacceptable employment practices. Materials also include Affirmative Action Program reports, a Superintendent's Bulletin on approved minority and women owned businesses, a Board Notice of Nondiscrimination for posting and distribution, an agenda from the October 10, 1988 Special Committee of the Whole meeting and the "Progress Report on Affirmative Action Program" presented at this meeting and bulletins on sexual harassment trainings and affirmative action/Title IX grievance procedures.
  - After School Education, 1996 December 2-2007 April 10 (Box 864, Folder 4-6)
    Board Communications and Reports on the expansion of LA's Best After-School Education and Enrichment Program, After School Education and Safety Program Service Providers Contracts and a report entitled "An Evaluation of After School Programs Provided by Partner Agencies of the Los Angeles Unified School District's Beyond the Bell Branch."
  - Agreements, 1939 April 3-2005 September 13 (Box 864, Folder 7-14, Box 876, Folder 1, Box 2060, Box 1699, Box 1700, Box 865, Box 866, Box 867, Box 868, Box 869, Box 870, Box 871, Box 872, Box 873, Box 874, Box 875)
    Board Communications, Committee Reports and correspondence concerning the District's contractual agreements with City, County, State Departments, institutions, groups, organizations, individuals, companies and corporations to provide services and implement programs such as a mental health institute, newspaper clipping service, elementary and high schools at juvenile hall, buildings, architecture, Cooperative Testing Service, mobile and relocatable classrooms, E-Z Sort System for student programming, the Jam Handy Organization for audio-visual materials, Joint Powers Act for the creation of the Youth Opportunities Board of Greater Los Angeles, gifted pupils, airlines, vocational training and job placement, teacher training program for educationally handicapped, implementation of Gender Equity Project "Women in Nontraditional Employment" program, General Relief Workfare Project Sponsorship, Parents Involved in Community Action, the Step-To-College program, the United Way to implement the Harbor Area Gang Alternative Program, Greater Avenues for Independence welfare reform program, the Institute for Successful Living and Soledad Enrichment Action, the Transition Partnership Program, the California Department of Education's Office of Homeless Children and Youth and School Police.
  - AIDS, 1991 June 6-2000 November 14 (Box 876, Folder 2-3)
    The Report to the Los Angeles Unified School District submitted June 6, 1991 by the Blue Ribbon Task Force on AIDS and a November 14, 2000 Board of Education Report authorizing Budget Services and Financial Planning Division to implement an Assembly Bill 11 AIDS Prevention Program for the 2000-2001 fiscal year.
  - Aircraft, 1967 September 1-1990 April 16 (Box 876, Folder 4)
    Bulletin on the District's policy concerning landing aircrafts on school sites, Committee of the Whole Communications authorizing helicopter landings on school sites, September 18, 1989 Communication from the Superintendent authorizing a sky diving performance at Locke High School's Homecoming celebration, Minutes related to the District's receipt of a jet aircraft from the United States Air Force to be used solely for instructional purposes, requests and approvals for Los Angeles Police Department helicopter landings on school sites, a copy of a Los Angeles Times article concerning landing approval despite community protests and a packet of protest materials presented to the Board on November 23, 1970 from the W.L.A. Community Protective Association opposing the Helistop on the roof of a previously approved police station on Iowa and Butler.
  - Air Pollution, 1948 June 10-1994 June 6 (Box 876, Folder 5-7, Box 877, Folder 1-5)
    Communications from Committees concerning compliance with AB2595, California Clean Air Act and the Air Quality Management District Regulations, copies of Findings and Decision of the Hearing Board of the Air Pollution Control District of Los Angeles County concerning school incinerator burning, combustible rubbish disposal and air contamination, County Counsel correspondence concerning the legal liabilities of the Board under the Air Pollution Control Act of 1947, San Fernando High School student letters urging the Board to notify all District schools when there is a first stage smog alert, school smog warning plans, county smog policy and a copy of a letter to the Los Angeles County Grand Jury from George L. Schuler concerning its investigation of the smog problem.
  - Alarms, 1972 December 21-2006 October 17 (Box 877, Folder 6-7)
    Board Minutes, Committee Reports and Reports of Correspondence concerning fire alarms and security alarm systems.
  - Alcohol, 1948 July 28-1999 October 26 (Box 877, Folder 8)
    Superintendent and Board Communications, Board Motions and Resolutions, Committee Reports, Bulletins and correspondence related to temperance education, the District's zero tolerance alcohol policy, K-9 detection units, prevention and treatment options.
  - Aliens, 1958 March 17-1999 October 26 (Box 877, Folder 9)
    Correspondence between Laurence L. Curran and Assistant Superintendent Virgil Volla concerning the interpretation of Section 1850 of the Labor Code and the employment of aliens.
  - All-City Choir, 1980 April 28 (Box 877, Folder 10)
    Instructional Planning Division Memo of April 28, 1980 for the Los Angeles Unified School District's All-City Choir performance on May 4, 1980 at the Scottish Rite Temple, 4357 Wilshire Boulevard.
  - Alternative Schools, 1972 June 5-1976 December 20 (Box 878, Folder 1-5)
    Reports of Correspondence, Board Communications, copies of Advisory Council Notes, Committee Reports, an Evaluation Report on Four Alternative Schools, a Progress Report on Year Round Schools, guidelines for Schools Within a School and 104 petitions of opposition to opening Rockdale as an Alternative School presented to the Board on December 12, 1974.
  - American Printing House for the Blind, 1916-1943 October 7 (Box 878, Folder 6)
    Board Communications, Standing Committee Reports, account statements, the Sixty-First Report of the Board of Trustees of the American Printing House for the Blind, an Acts of Legislation Affecting the American Printing House for the Blind pamphlet and correspondence concerning the Los Angeles City Schools' account with this printing house for the purpose of aiding the education of the blind in the United States.
  - Americans With Disabilities, 1990 October 1 (Box 879, Folder 1)
    Inter-Office Correspondence concerning the Americans With Disabilities Act of 1990 and its effect on the LAUSD.
  - Animals, 1973 May 24-1990 July 31 (Box 879, Folder 2)
    Board Bulletins, Reports of Correspondence and Standing Committee Communications regarding animal bite reporting procedures, the use of animals in biomedical research, the treatment of live animals in the classroom, the maintenance of animals in agricultural and environmental education and Assembly Bill 2344 proposing a ban on the use of steel-jaw traps to capture animals.
  - Annexation, 1915 May 25-2000 November 14 (Box 879, Folder 3-14, Box 880, Box 881, Box 882, Box 883, Folder 1-9)
    Copies of Board Communications, Standing Committee Reports, California Superior Court Actions, petitions, correspondence, agreements, maps and newspaper clippings related to the annexations and withdrawals of schools, districts and land areas to and from the Los Angeles City School Districts.
    Materials include the following transfers of territories, Annexation Districts, school districts and school sites: Bee Elementary School District, Hancock Park School, Jordan High School, Lawndale School District, Lynwood Unified School District, Laurel School, Rosewood Avenue School, Indiana Street School, Santa Clarita Union High School District, Newhall High School, the Western Avenue Highlands Addition, Alhambra City School District, Beverly Hills Unified School District, Burbank Unified School District, McClure Addition, Benmar Hills, Compton Unified School District, Crenshaw Boulevard Annexation, Vista Pacifica Annexation Nos. 1 and 2, Culver City Elementary School District, Culver City High School District, Culver City Unified School District, Downey Unified School District, Gardena High School, Glendale Unified School District, Tuna Canyon Addition No. 2, Whiting Woods, Holly Park Area, Four Cities Area (Bell, Maywood, Huntington Park, Vernon), 111th Street Area, East Lennox Territory, La Brea-Slauson Annexation, 110th Street Territory, Ladera Heights Area, Shoestring Strip Territory, Inglewood Unified School District, Inglewood Knolls Area, Century Park School, 113th Street Territory, 108th Street Territory, El Monte Union High School District, Alhambra City High School District, Montebello Unified School District, Burbank Unified District, Las Virgenes Unified School District, Lennox School District, Long Beach Unified School District, Marina Del Rey Junior High School, East Los Angeles Junior College, Old River School District, Palos Verdes Peninsula School District, Montecillo Area, Hollywood Riviera Area, San Fernando School District, Morningside School District, Owensmouth School District, Santa Monica Unified School District, South Gate, Topanga School District, Lomita Flight Strip (Barrow Pit) Annexation, Torrance City School District, Willowbrook School District and Windsor Hills Area.
  - Annuity Reserve Fund, 1972 May 5-2004 April 22 (Box 883, Folder 10-13, Box 884, Folder 1-3)
    The Annuity Reserve Fund was established on July 1, 1972 with a fund balance of $31 million in bonds, long-term notes, common stock and short-term investments. Materials include Annuity Reserve Fund Board Meeting Agendas, signed Oaths of Office for Members of the Annuity Reserve Fund Board, copies of Committee of the Whole Reports, Annuity Reserve Fund Board Rules, statements of candidates for election to the Annuity Reserve Fund Board and election materials.
  - Apartheid, 1985 August 19-1985 September 9 (Box 884, Folder 4)
    Copies of an anti-apartheid Board Resolution presented by Board member Rita Walters and an anti-apartheid Board Resolution presented by Board member Jackie Goldberg, both carried by the Board in 1985.
  - Applications, 1937 January 26-2004 January 13 (Box 884, Folder 5-7, Box 885, Box 886, Folder 1-7)
    Applications for architectural services, the Innovative Projects Fund, educational programs, State Aid, correspondence concerning employment with the District and Standing Committee and Board of Education Reports authorizing the filing of applications.
  - Apportionments, 1937 July 10-1957 April 8 (Box 886, Folder 8)
    Copies of correspondence, a 1957 California Teachers Association pamphlet, Board Communications, a 1955 press release from the State Board of Equalization and Reports from the Budget Division and Finance Committee.
  - Appreciation, 1948 June 15-1978 April 10 (Box 2061, Box 1701, Box 887, Box 888, Box 889, Box 890, Box 891)
    Correspondence, Minutes, newspaper clippings, greeting cards and post cards of commendation for employees of the District.
  - Appropriations, 1940 November 14-2004 February 10 (Box 892, Folder 1-2)
    Copies of Board Reports, Budget and Finance Committee Reports, Committee of the Whole Reports, Memoranda and Board Communications prepared by the Budget Division.
  - Architects, 1954 April 1-1995 October 2 (Box 892, Folder 3-5)
    Building Committee Reports, transcriptions of Committee of the Whole meetings, correspondence between the Board and potential architects, Board Communications concerning the use of developer fees for Accelerated School Apportionment Program Projects (ASAP), the Adrian Wilson and Associates brochure, "Building a Better World" and a copy of The School Executive article, "It's Time to Look at Tomorrow's Schools" by Robert E. Alexander of the Neutra and Alexander firm.
  - Art Collection, 2000 May 23-2008 April 5 (Box 892, Folder 6)
    A copy of the May 23, 2000 Board Resolution concerning its endorsement of the grant application to the Getty Grant Foundation for the preservation of the District's fine art collection and the following Los Angeles Times articles: "Venice Grads Want Myrna Loy, the Statue, to Take Another Bow" and "Schools' Art Cache Is a Study in Forgotten Treasures."
  - Artist-In-Residence, 2000 May 23-2008 April 5 (Box 892, Folder 7)
    Board Communications approving agreements with the California Arts Council (CAC), MIKO (Brownislow Machalski), Free Public Theatre Foundation, Self Help Graphics, Art Inc. and Valentina Oumansky Dramatic Dance Foundation to provide Artist-In-Residence services at numerous school sites.
  - Arts Education Program, 1998 February 9-2009 May 11 (Box 892, Folder 8-9)
    Reports and correspondence pertaining to the LAUSD Arts Education Plan established by Board's adoption of a resolution on June 22, 1999. The plan calls for a comprehensive, sequential, standards-based arts education for all students in the District.
  - Asbestos Abatement, 2000 February 22-2008 May 22 (Box 893, Folder 1)
    Proposals for asbestos abatement projects.
  - Assessments, 1955 March 28-1996 June 17 (Box 893, Folder 3-4)
    Board Bulletins, Standing Committee Reports and correspondence concerning both assessments of student achievement and of taxable property valuations.
  - Athletics, 1946 November 19-1996 June 17 (Box 893, Folder 5-10)
    Brochures, correspondence, schedules, Memoranda and press releases for baseball, the California Interscholastic Federation Protection Fund, track, soccer, football and its popular Milk Bowl Games.
  - Attacks, 1975 October 16-1976 January 5 (Box 893, Folder 11)
    Copies of correspondence concerning attacks on school personnel.
  - Attendance, 1945 January 4-2005 December 13 (Box 895, Folder 1-4, Box 894, Box 1702)
    Correspondence, press releases, Board actions on expulsions, copies of truancy details for a Jane and John Doe, typed notes for Board member Eleanor B. Allen's panel discussion on juvenile delinquency, Committee of the Whole notes on the abolition of the District's Truancy Detail, Annual Reports from the Child Welfare and Attendance Branch and newspaper clippings and correspondence concerning the Board's November 19, 1945 expulsion approval for 92 Hollenbeck Junior High School who left their classes on November 2, 1945 to protest the Board granting a permit to Gerald L.K. Smith to speak in a school auditorium.
    Materials also include transcripts of Board discussion on the student walkouts and the recommended expulsions of Roosevelt High student sit-in and blowout organizers, interdistrict pupil attendance forms, reports of average daily attendance and enrollment by schools, an Educational Development Committee Report on the establishment of 29 necessary small high schools for continuation education, a Superintendent Communication concerning overcrowded schools that includes density guidelines per acre and procedures concerning emergency situations such as lockdowns, explosions, police barricades, fires and other natural disasters.
  - Auction, 2003 September 9-2006 October 24 (Box 895, Folder 5)
    Facilities Service Division Board of Education Report, "Auction for the Salvage of Items and the Sale and Relocation of Buildings" and a Business Services Division Board of Education Report, "Authorization to Solicit Proposals, Conduct a Price Discovery Auction or Similar Process, and Execute Supply Contracts for Transportation Fuels or Other Emergency Commodities and Related Services."
  - Auditoriums, 1962 March 23-2000 June 27 (Box 895, Folder 6)
    Facilities Reports, Committee of the Whole Reports, Reports of Correspondence and copies of Applications For Use Of School Property concerning requests to use school auditoriums.
  - Audio Visual, 1942-1992 July 6 (Box 895, Folder 7-10)
    Los Angeles City Schools' "Audio-Visual News" catalogs, "'Participation: The Last Word in Films'" brochure by Bruce Allyn Findlay, Los Angeles City Schools Head Supervisor of Visual Education, "The Audio-Visual Projectionist's Handbook," Audio-Visual catalogs for elementary and secondary grades, Committee Reports, correspondence and Bulletins concerning audio-visual educational materials.
  - Audits and Auditors, 1950 June 7-2011 September 11 (Box 896, Box 897, Box 898, Box 899, Box 900, Box 901, Box 902, Box 903, Box 904, Folder 1-3)
    Contract Auditors' Reports, progress reports, bulletins, Budget and Finance Committee Reports, Committee of the Whole meeting notes, Auditors and Administrative Advisory Committee Minutes, Comprehensive Annual Financial Reports, Management Review Final Report by Arthur Andersen & Co., Report Upon Special Studies of Warehousing Supplies and Equipment of the Los Angeles School Districts and Reports Upon Examinations of the Los Angeles City School Districts by certified public accountants, Thomas & Moore, Lybrand, Ross Bros. & Montgomery and Peat, Marwick, Mitchell & Co. concerning examinations of the District's financial statements and accounts. There are no Reports Upon Examination for Year Ended June 30, 1952 and 1965.
  - Automobiles, 1946 December 11-1988 November 14 (Box 904, Folder 4-5)
    Correspondence, Committee Reports and Communications related to policies for use and assignment of District cars and limousines, radio system for buses and the Driver Training Program.
  - Band (Marching), 1980 June 9-1989 August 24 (Box 904, Folder 6)
    Bulletins, Committee Communications, Committee Reports and Board resolutions of commendation concerning guidelines for performances by school bands at football games, corporate sponsorship by the Coca Cola Bottling Company of Los Angeles and Pepsi Co., the Jazz Band Program, accident insurance and Band and Drill Team Championships.
  - Banks, 1973 October 29-2002 October 22 (Box 905, Folder 1)
    Committee Reports, Board resolutions, Board Communications, Memoranda and Bulletins concerning agreements for banking services, authorizations of banking accounts, student body organization checking accounts, the Auxiliary Services Trust Fund, the Liability Self-Insurance Fund program, authorization for Controller to sign warrants, changes in authorized signatures and banking information materials from United California Bank.
  - Basic Activities, 1981 July 20-1988 July 18 (Box 905, Folder 2)
    Correspondence, memoranda, copies of the District publication "Spotlight," a transcript of remarks made by Superintendent Handler at a Committee of the Whole Budget Meeting, Basic Activities: A Resource Guide for Principals issued by Deputy Superintendent William R. Anton, Superintendent Harry Handler's Basic Activities: Goals to Achieve... Principles to Follow guiding document and Statement and a Goals and Principles, Los Angeles Unified School District brochure presented to the Board by Superintendent Handler.
  - Basic Skills Improvement Unit, 1984 May 4-1995 June 19 (Box 905, Folder 3-4)
    Committee Reports and correspondence concerning the GAIN Basic Skills Program, the California Educational Initiatives Fund (CEIF), authorization to submit initial applications to the United States Office of Education for Basic Skills Improvement Programs, results of the 1983-84 California Assessment Program (CAP) and a Review of Superintendent Zacarias' 7 Benchmark Performance Indicators.
  - Belmont Commission, 1999 August-1999 November (Box 2105, Box 2106, Box 2107, Box 2108, Box 2109)
    111 VHS tapes.
    73 audio cassette tapes.
    BOXES CONTAIN AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    On August 20, 1999, the Board established the Belmont Commission and charged it to review the following issues with respect to the proposed Belmont Learning Center: 1.) Policy Options; 2.) Risk Levels; 3.) Fail-safe Environment Mitigation; 4.) Seismic Activity; 5.) Liability and Insurance; 6.) Disclosure and Choice; and 7.) Public Acceptance.
    The Report of the Independent Commission Regarding the Belmont Learning Center includes conclusions and recommendations, a review of environmental studies, presentations, public input, legal issues, public health hazards, seismic analysis and remediation and mitigation.
    The Report also includes attachments such as correspondence from parents of children who attend Esperanza Elementary School, the Department of Toxic Substances Control and Senator Richard G. Polanco.
    The Report contains an index of documents submitted to the Belmont Commission. As of October 26, 1999, these files were located at LAUSD Administration, 450 North Grand Avenue, Los Angeles, in Room G-280, the Commission office.
    The following boxes include materials pertaining to the Belmont Independent Commission (BIC):
    Box 2,105: List of Belmont Commission Meetings, correspondence to the Board from BIC Executive Director Ira Reiner regarding the BIC's decision not to proceed with the Project and Report of Independent Commission Regarding the Belmont Learning Center.
    Box 2,106: Twenty-one VHS recordings from the BIC meeting dates that fall between September 13, 1999 through October 20, 1999.
    Box 2,107: Thirty VHS recordings from the BIC meeting dates that fall between October 16, 1999 through November 11, 1999.
    Box 2,108: Thirty-four VHS recordings from the BIC meeting dates that fall between August 23, 1999 through October 15, 1999.
    Box 2,109: Twenty-six VHS recordings from the BIC meeting dates that fall between September 16, 1999 through October 7, 1999.
    Box 2,109: Seventy-two audio cassette tapes from the BIC meeting dates that fall between August 16, 1999 through November 11, 1999 and one Board/Superintendent Press conference cassette tape from September 16, 1999.
  - Bench Contracts, 2003 October 14-2005 June 28 (Box 905, Folder 5)
    Information Technology Division (ITD) Reports concerning authorizations for ITD Bench contracts for IT professional services.
  - Bequests, 1940 June 13-1986 June 16 (Box 905, Folder 6-16)
    Committee Communications, Committee Reports, correspondence, copies of Superior Court of the State of California notices of hearings for confirmation of the sale of real estate and bequests from individuals and estates related to the District's Scholarship Trust Funds.
  - Bereavement, 1948 July 29-1991 August 19 (Box 907, Folder 1-2, Box 905, Folder 17-18, Box 906)
    Condolence correspondence and statements from Minutes concerning the passing of District employees, their friends, family and leaders such as General Douglas MacArthur, Eleanor Roosevelt, Ralph Bunche and Marcus Foster.
  - Bicentennial, 1980 April 17-1981 December 7 (Box 907, Folder 3)
    Superintendent Communications, Minutes, a school coordinators kick off meeting agenda and a memorandum concerning the Bicentennial of the City of Los Angeles.
  - Bicycle, 1989 July 17-1997 July 21 (Box 907, Folder 4)
    Board of Education Reports and Superintendent Communications concerning the Bike LA/Safety Training (BLAST) program, the Bicycle Commuting and Safety Education Video Program (BCSEVP) and funding for bicycle yards at various schools.
  - Bids, 1937 February 1-2003 May 13 (Box 907, Folder 5-9, Box 1722, Folder 1-2)